<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Alex's Dev Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/gamechallenge.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2015-04-15T16:46:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Space Invaders</title><link href="/space-invaders.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-15T16:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-15:space-invaders.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Space Invaders project is meant to be two-fold. I'm using it to learn more about the language C++ but also to learn more about how my programming choices affect the computer, such as where things are being stored in memory. While learning is one of the most important parts of this project, completing the game is important as well. I've started laying out the different classes I will need to make the game as well as the different types of functions I'll need in each class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="learncpp.com"&gt;Learning C++&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While looking for resources to learn C++ I came across a website that not only has a lot of information about C++, but also has a ton of other more basic information for programming. I've started working my way through this website, which is laid out like a web based book. At the end of each chapter there is a comprehensive quiz that covers most of what was talked about throughout the chapter, along with the answers so you can make sure you did it correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Data Structures &amp;amp; Algorithms(DSA)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I've spent most of my time diving into C++ so I can get a good grasp of the differences between it and other languages I've used a lot of, I'm also getting started with DSA. I've borrowed a couple of different books that cover these topics and will be starting to read through them in the next couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="HFOSS"></category><category term="BizLeg"></category><category term="GameChallenge"></category></entry><entry><title>GDC Day 5</title><link href="/gdc-day-5.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-21T22:08:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-21:gdc-day-5.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Dawn of the Last Day&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last day was short, both in how long I was at the conference, and in how long it was open. I walked around the expo floor for a little bit, and ran into the CA I had met before the production roundtable. After that I went to a second production roundtable. This one had many more people and was about managing and motivating people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lunch and Exploration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the production roundtable I played some Tumblestone until it was time to meet up with some RIT people and some new friends for some lunch. We walked around San Francisco some, playing a game where when you come to an intersection you cross the street in whichever direction turns green first. Even though we didn't really do much besides walk around, it was a nice way to destress before heading back to the cold insanity that is Rochester.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category><category term="HFOSS"></category><category term="GameChallenge"></category></entry><entry><title>GDC Day 4</title><link href="/gdc-day-4.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-15T16:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-15:gdc-day-4.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Early Morning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After grabbing breakfast, I introduced a friend to an ex-coworker, hopefully starting a conversation for an internship position. We then made our way over to the Razer booth to talk to them and try to get in their development program for their fitness band. In order to get in you were supposed to prove that you have some mobile development chops, but I started talking Twine2Unity, which my only mobile stuff and the guy got extremely excited that somebody was doing something interesting with Twine. I then wandered around and talked to people about what they're currently developing and getting some awesome new shirts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anti-Social Behavior Talk&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting some new swag and talking to developers trying to learn as much as I can, I went to a talk about how design enforces anti-social behavior. It was given by a researcher who has talked to different companies who have recognized that their games have toxic communities. Even though it's hard to design in a way that rewards good behavior without adding to the punishment of the toxic players, it's extremely important to start thinking about it. The earlier we as developers can start iterating on ideas, the quicker we can try and get the problem fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Production Round Table&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wandering around more, and talking with some companies in the career fair I went to a production round table. It was down at the end of what looked like a mostly unused hallway. When I walked down there one of the CA's asked if I was lost, but I just wanted to get their early in case there were a lot of people. After that we started talking, she got extremely excited because she was coming off shift and is wanting to get into production. It started off as a conversation more about how to get into production, which was cool for those of us who are trying to get in. We then moved into more of a discussion around getting better at your job, or just general advice for producers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were definitely some interesting conversations going on both during and afterwards. One of the people who was there is a Senior Producer at Blizzard(World of Warcraft), and another is a producer from CCP(Eve Online). After, the producer from CCP had a bunch of questions for the guy from Blizzard. He was trying to learn as much as he can so he can try to bring new things back to his company to make them more successful. I wanted to learn as much as I can to help jump start my career. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their conversation about how both studios deal with production the guy from Blizzard and I started talking. I talked about my Diabetes add-on, which he seemed extremely interested in, and then we started talking about career advice, and the fact that I was about to be headed to the Blizzard recruitment mixer came up. He told me I should say hi to a specific lady for him when I got there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blizzard Mixer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I made it to the bar that the Mixer was supposed to be at, there was a giant line going down the block and then around the corner. I walked back to where a couple of my friends for waiting for me, and where they were talking with some other friends as well. I ended up speaking with some really interesting people while waiting in line to get in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finally getting in, I asked for the Lady that the Blizzard producer had told me to say hi for and found her really quickly. We had an interesting conversation about why I had a lanyard indicating that I wanted to be a programmer but had met the producer at a production roundtable. She then told me that I should talk to a specific programmer who was somewhere in the back of the bar and found someone to lead me back to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was in the middle of a conversation with another developer about what he does as a lead and to me it sounded like he has become more of a producer than a programmer, but he was still able to talk programming with me. I had learned earlier in the week that the UI/UX team and Gameplay programming team use the same API that add-on developers have access to, just with some extra protected functions. I asked him about that - about what it was like to be using something that seems more like it was created with add-on developers in mind, and he said while at times it was annoying, it makes a lot of sense. A lot of the different portions of the game are basically just add-ons that are loaded when the player gets within a certain range of where they would be interacting with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that first conversation the rest of the night was me being whirlwinded around and being introduced to a bunch of people or just walking up and introducing myself to people. Which overall was a ton of fun.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category><category term="HFOSS"></category><category term="GameChallenge"></category></entry><entry><title>GDC Day 3</title><link href="/gdc-day-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-09T02:04:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-09:gdc-day-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Starbucks and Game Devs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting coffee this morning turned into me pitching WoW Diabetes to a WoW dev.  Apparently they have a list of things they do when they need a break or are extra stressed, and he added this to the list. I can't wait to keep working on this and start really polishing it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Audio Designer and More Coffee&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While waiting for the Expo floor to open I was standing near the line for one of the coffee places inside the convention center, I was asked multiple times if I was in line as well. When one of them asked me, I finally got up the nerves to ask him what he does and try to start a conversation. It turned out that he's a freelance audio designer, but he worked for multiple different companies before going off on his own. Because of this he knows a ton of people and after talking about the projects I'm working on now, he was more than willing to drag me around the conference introducing me to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Spritebuilder&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While wandering around the expo floor, I saw a poster for something called Spritebuilder. Underneath the name it claimed to be an open source game development suite. After delving into open source software in the past year or so I was interested in seeing more about it. One of their developers was showing it to me and we talked about it being open source. The developer told me it's base code is a project called Cocos2d which was already an open source project. So naturally they followed in it's footsteps. The development software itself looks to be a mixture of Flash and Unity specifically for iOS development. I can't wait to have time to play around with it more and see what I can and can't do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blizzard Programmer Panel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the middle of the day the Blizzard University Relations team had an organized panel focusing on programming. The panel was made up of people from most of the different teams within Blizzard, as well as having people of all different levels within the company. They had a lot of good information, and pretty much everyone asked good questions. Afterwards most of the Blizzard employees who were there stuck around to answer more questions and talk to people. I of course talked about WoW Diabetes. A couple of times the response was that they didn't work on the WoW team, but I took a chance and replied, but you probably play some WoW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Early Night&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple more hours of walking around and talking with people, I decided to call it an early night. I spent some time working on a bit of homework, then played some games before getting to sleep early. After having stayed up late Sunday through Tuesday I figured it was a good idea to get some extra rest so I could be refreshed for the rest of the week.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category><category term="HFOSS"></category><category term="GameChallenge"></category></entry><entry><title>GDC Day 2</title><link href="/gdc-day-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-08T13:58:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-08:gdc-day-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Random Talking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today has been so much better. I guess I just needed some time to get used to having so many people around. I got the chance to talk to a lot of fun people. There weren't any talks that sounded interesting, so instead I mostly just walked around and said hi to as many people as I could. I also took the time to go play one of the board games in the table top lounge. I looked at what all games they had, and while I wish I had taken the time to play the XCOM board game, I really enjoyed the game I did play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mascarade&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mascarade is a board game that doesn't use a board. You have a bunch of different cards that represent different roles. The roles that are in play for each game are dependent on how many players are playing. The different roles have different abilities that help players reach their goal. Each player starts with six gold and the point of the game is to get to thirteen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a players turn you can take one of three actions: you can swap your role card with another players(under the table so no one knows which role you kept), you can look at your card(so you know who you are), or you can announce who you are and use your ability. If somebody thinks/knows you're lying about who you are they can clame to be that person, at which point both players flip over their roles. If both players are different roles from the one claimed, they pay a one gold penalty, otherwise whichever player was incorrect pays the penalty and the other player gets to activate the ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winning this game requires a lot of paying attention to what's going on, which may not have been one of the best things to play at a conference where you want to talk and meet people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Christine Love&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw Christine just standing around talking while I was in the Indie Megabooth. I sort of geeked out and didn't know what to say. Her writing is amazing, and I can't wait to see what she has in store with her next game. I also got to talk with her about Twine2Unity, a parser I've been working on with a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Sha of Happiness&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got to meet the Sha of Happiness. She created a roleplaying Twitter account based on an idea from the World of Warcraft. Throughout her time on Twitter, she's gone back and forth on whether or not she's roleplaying. She's spent some of her time talking about depression and how she deals with it, which in turn has helped me deal with learning to deal with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had asked her if we could meet up, but I definitely wasn't expecting to see her when I did. It was only a few minutes after running into Christine Love and I was still shaking with excitement. It took everything I had not to run over in excitement when I recognized her. We sat and talked for awhile, and then ended up getting ice cream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm extremely glad that I got the opportunity to meet her in person, and I really hope that we can have more interactions. She is an amazingly friendly person, and she's willing to stand up and fight for what she believes in. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category><category term="HFOSS"></category><category term="GameChallenge"></category></entry><entry><title>GDC Day 1</title><link href="/gdc-day-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-03T00:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-03:gdc-day-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Stress and Over Saturation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the awesome opportunity to go to E3 this past summer. I thought having that experience under my belt would help me deal with the shear number of people around here. I was insanely wrong. As the day has gone on it's gotten slightly better. I spent a lot of time hanging with the people who were running a little game corner called the Wheel of Whimsy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Meeting People&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did meet a couple of people, someone who graduated with a 3D animation degree, but loves gaming and wants to break into the industry. I also met an awesome gentleman who does content production for a company that works for the DOD. I also met a man who was trying to do a report on GDC this year, and was taking quotes for the Facebook based newspaper he works, you can read it at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10152941545385817.1073743432.171020735816&amp;amp;type=1"&gt;SFNews.US&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category><category term="HFOSS"></category><category term="GameChallenge"></category></entry></feed>