<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Alex's Dev Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/litreviews.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2015-03-28T14:48:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Nobel Popular Economics</title><link href="/nobel-popular-economics.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-28T14:48:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-28:nobel-popular-economics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Who&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jean Tirole&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popular Science Background for the Nobel Prize in Economic Sciences 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bizlegfoss-ritigm.rhcloud.com/static/books/nobel-popular-economicsciences2014.pdf"&gt;Popular Science Background for the Nobel Prize in Economic Sciences 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is a quick summary of the 2014 Nobel Prize in economics, which included research that showed earlier research may be true for some cases but isn't true for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He addressed oligopolies which isn't talked about very often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He proved that game theory can be important outside of the realm of games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a fairly short read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It needs more useful visualizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It could use some examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It didn't seem to have much really about code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.
2.
3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Your Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was an interesting read, however it was very short and could have benefited greatly from examples and visualizations that were meaningful. It didn't really have anything to do with code other than the game theory mention.
2 Red Roses&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry><entry><title>Using GPL'd Software In-House and the OSI Business Model</title><link href="/using-gpld-software-in-house-and-the-osi-business-model.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-28T02:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-28:using-gpld-software-in-house-and-the-osi-business-model.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Who&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using GPL'd Software In-House&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bradley M. Kuhn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anthony K. Sebro, Jr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denver Gingerich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The OSI Business Model&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Source Initiative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copyleft and the GNU General Public License: A Comprehensive Tutorial and Guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Source Case for Business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bizlegfoss-ritigm.rhcloud.com/static/books/comprehensive-gpl-guide.pdf&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank"&gt;Copyleft and the GNU General Public License: A Comprehensive Tutorial and Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://opensource.org/advocacy/case_for_business.php"&gt;Open Source Case for Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Originally released in 2003 but has seen many updates with the latest being in 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last "Updated" in 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies can use GPL'd software throughout a company without having to worry about anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are advantages and disadvantages from most of the different business perspectives. There are four "known" business models for open source money making: Support sellers, loss leader, widget frosting, and accessorizing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's short and to the point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPL'd Software can be shared throughout a company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While it's not often advertised to the regular consumer, there are a lot of big name products that are open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While it being short is nice, it also means theres not a lot of substance or explanation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples are out of date. While it's nice to have them in there, if the people reading it don't know what the example is, it's not very helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This really only deals with the theoretical, and the theoretical isn't always how things pan out in practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are other licenses dealt with when trying to use them for company purposes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are these all of the possible FOSS business models that are in use? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we show companies that FOSS isn't necessarily a bad thing? That you can make money off of it and it might actually make your product better?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using GPL'd Software is a short and sweet section of what is potentially a great book. It offers an interesting piece of information without bogging the reader down in too much unneeded info.
6 Red Roses and 6 White Roses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSI Business Model is a much longer read. While it has some really good information, there is a lot that is outdated. It has broken links and examples that not everyone will have heard of.
8 Red Roses&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry><entry><title>Organizational Issues</title><link href="/organizational-issues.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-28T02:10:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-03-28:organizational-issues.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Who&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Fontana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bradley M. Kuhn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eben Moglen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew Norwood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel B. Ravicher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karen Sandler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Vasile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aaron Williamson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects - Chapter 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bizlegfoss-ritigm.rhcloud.com/static/books/foss-primer.pdf&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank"&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 4, 2008&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter provides a brief overview of organizational issues, and how you might go about choosing if you want to create your own organization for your project or try to join another organization with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reiteration that this is not legal advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a seemingly straightforward guide to incorporating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This chapter just addresses the legal issues of having an organization and not any of the social ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The information in this chapter is even more localized than the other chapters, dealing mostly with New York's requirements when other chapters talked about the entire US.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There still aren't really any examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are digital board meetings not counted as the same as a board meeting in person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are some examples of different successful open source organizations?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does dealing with incorporating or other organizational things when not all of the developers are from a single country?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter contains a lot of good, although basic, information about how to become a corporation if needed. It also talks about some of the different reasons that you may or may not want to do so. Over all it is a very generalized chapter, and only goes into some specifics, such as how NY state deals with out of state corporations.
6 Red Roses&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category><category term="HFOSS"></category></entry><entry><title>Trademarks and Your Foss Project</title><link href="/trademarks-and-your-foss-project.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-26T14:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-26:trademarks-and-your-foss-project.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;#ianyl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Who&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen Sandler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trademarks and Your Free and Open Source Software Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JY6AtbtAuts"&gt;Trademarks and Your Free and Open Source Software Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October 22, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trademarks are a very complicated matter. It's important to keep your mark and to keep it distinguished. But in the FOSS community it's extremely important that you don't push your users away but having an overly strict Trademark policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even though she's a lawyer, she's also very clear that this isn't legal advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She is very clear about everything and uses a lot of different types of examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FDA doesn't review the code on medical devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She says umm a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It sounds like she's talking faster than normal, and not breathing naturally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have to do more than just protect your mark from genericide?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you've done everything that you can
3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karen does a really good job of breaking down Trademarks so that pretty much anybody can understand them. She uses a lot of examples to help get her point across and to help with understanding.
A dozen white roses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry><entry><title>Common Trademark Issues</title><link href="/common-trademark-issues.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-24T14:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-24:common-trademark-issues.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Who&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Fontana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bradley M. Kuhn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eben Moglen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew Norwood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel B. Ravicher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karen Sandler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Vasile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aaron Williamson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects - Chapter 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bizlegfoss-ritigm.rhcloud.com/static/books/foss-primer.pdf&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank"&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 4, 2008&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This contains a general overview of Trademarks. You shouldn't try to trademark a generic name such as "music player". Unlike with patents, you should search Trademarks, including things that are unregistered. Registering yours give you stronger protection that not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They're very clear you should seek profession advice if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely thourough amounts of information, such as pricing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike in the Patents, they gave a clear example when talking about giving permission for outside people to use a trademark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's no examples for what might count as a specimen outside of what the USPTO requires.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This chapter didn't speak at all to laws outside of the US and how that might affect software projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who gets to decide that genericide has happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have to pay more money to update your mark?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What defines a thorough search?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter gave a very good overview of Trademarks and some good examples of how to use one or to deal with other people using them. It reiterates
5 Red Roses&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry><entry><title>Promises: Red Hat, IBM Patent, Google Patent, Comparisons</title><link href="/promises-red-hat-ibm-patent-google-patent-comparisons.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-20T16:43:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-20:promises-red-hat-ibm-patent-google-patent-comparisons.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Who&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Hat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greg DeKoenigsberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Hat Patent Promise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM Patent Promise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Patent Pledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patent Promise Comparisons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.redhat.com/legal/patent_policy.html"&gt;Red Hat Patent Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com/ibm/licensing/patents/pledgedpatents.pdf"&gt;IBM Patent Promise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/patents/opnpledge/pledge/"&gt;Google Patent Pledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/magazine/001nov04/features/patents/"&gt;Patent Promise Comparisons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Date Given&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Date Given&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Date Given&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple companies have published promises that they won't come after open source projects for patent infringement of certian patents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Hat is standing against patents, and even though they hold some, if your software is free and open source, and under one of their approved licenses they won't target you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies are at least somewhat trying to allow open source to thrive, even when it might be something that company owns a patent for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These help to promote the open source community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too much legalese. It would be awesome if someone who knows legalese would take things like these and put them in layman's terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of these companies are still more interested in protecting themselves than they are helping out the open source community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even after digging in to some of the legalese, they still seem fairly vague.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did these companies amass all of their patents?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Hat seems to be trying to help protect open source but the others seem more interested in protecting themselves. Is this true?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there any times where someone has ended up in a legal battle with one of these companies after they published their promises?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These promises provide a lot of information about specific patents that are currently held by differenet companies, and how that affects the open source community. 
Half a dozen red roses and 3 white roses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry><entry><title>Patent Defenses for FOSS Developers</title><link href="/patent-defenses-for-foss-developers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-16T23:29:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-16:patent-defenses-for-foss-developers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Who&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Fontana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bradley M. Kuhn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eben Moglen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew Norwood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel B. Ravicher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karen Sandler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Vasile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aaron Williamson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects - Chapter 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bizlegfoss-ritigm.rhcloud.com/static/books/foss-primer.pdf&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank"&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 4, 2008&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reading a patent it is recommended to start with the claims, as this is the "legally binding" portion. The file wrapper is also important as it could contain statements that limit the patent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The footnotes hold some interesting and potentially useful information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once again the authors are very clear that they aren't trying to give legal advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This gives a good overview of how patents work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This chapter was much more dry and harder to read than previous chapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be helpful to have an example showing what they're talking about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a very foreboding chapter, that makes it seem like patents could ruin everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The idea of willful infringement doesn't really make sense, just because you know about something doesn't mean you realized that you used it. How do they prove willful infringement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the "file wrapper" the legal name for those documents, or is that a colloquialism because they're talking specifically about software?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do they decide if you're ex parte or inter partes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter was extremely dry and didn't have much information past what is a patent and a few ways you might be able to get past patent infringement. It would have benefitted greatly from having an example patent, even if it wasn't a legitimate patent.
2 Red Roses&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry><entry><title>iTunes TOS, Fedora Project Contributors Agreement, Python Software Foundation CLA</title><link href="/itunes-tos-fedora-project-contributors-agreement-python-software-foundation-cla.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-12T14:04:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-12:itunes-tos-fedora-project-contributors-agreement-python-software-foundation-cla.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Who&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fedora&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTunes TOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fedora Project Contributors Agreement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Software Foundation CLA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/us/terms.html"&gt;iTunes TOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Legal:Fedora_Project_Contributor_Agreement"&gt;Fedora Project Contributors Agreement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://legacy.python.org/psf/contrib/contrib-form/contributor-agreement.pdf"&gt;Python Software Foundation CLA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last Updated: September 17, 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last Updated: February 2, 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last Updated: No Date Given&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iTunes agreement applies to everyone who uses either the iTunes program on their computer or any of the iDevice line of electronics. The Python and Fedor agreements apply to anyone who wants to work on the projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These documents illustrate the importance of clarification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In comparison to other documents of similar ilk, these weren't long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These documents were extremely descriptive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a lot of "legalese".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All caps through some sections makes it extremely hard to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having an FAQ at the top might help people understand what it's saying a bit better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can Apple really tell the "organizer" that they can't have access to something an ex "family member" downloaded even though the "organizer" paid for it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTunes Usage rule III&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are TOS and EULA's legally binding?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reading is extremely dry and strewn with legalese. It's not even really clear if they're legally binding. 
2 Red Roses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry><entry><title>What is Open Source and How Does it Work</title><link href="/what-is-open-source-and-how-does-it-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-09T16:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-09:what-is-open-source-and-how-does-it-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Who&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steven Weber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Success of Open Source - Chapter 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://hfoss-ritigm.rhcloud.com/static/books/Weber-SuccessofOpenSource-Chap3.pdf&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank"&gt;The Success of Open Source - Chapter 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;November 30, 2005&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining how and why open source projects work is a very complicated matter. It doesn't follow the normal programming flow. It is fairly impossible to know how many people contribute to the open source community, or to know those peoples motivations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like the use of she for the pronoun instead of having a majority of hes throughout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a decent number of graphs to help show data as they talk about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It compares code to both poetry and midieval architectures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of the footnotes being at the bottom of the pages it seems they're all at the end of the book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It really bothers me that the author will start talking about something and then say he'll talk more about it in a different chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely in-depth, sometimes too much so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why were VA Linux and Red Hat Software so successful out of the gate on Wall Street?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If Brooke's Law is true, why are there so many extremely large programming teams? Wouldn't it make more sense to have smaller teams?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where did the term hostile forking originate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're new in the land of open source, this text contains a lot of useful knowledge about the history of open source and open source communities.
Half a dozen red roses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="HFOSS"></category></entry><entry><title>GNU GPL Chapter 1</title><link href="/gnu-gpl-chapter-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-08T18:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-08:gnu-gpl-chapter-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Who&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bradley M. Kuhn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anthony K. Sebro, Jr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denver Gingerich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyleft and the GNU General Public License: A Comprehensive Tutorial and Guide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bizlegfoss-ritigm.rhcloud.com/static/books/comprehensive-gpl-guide.pdf&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank"&gt;Copyleft and the GNU General Public License: A Comprehensive Tutorial and Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Gist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software Freedom encompasses multiple different ideas, and different license types give different ammounts of freedom. Copyright is also an important part of dealing with free software, even though copyright is normally seen as taking away freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The information is broken down to make it feel more readable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's a lot of interesting information about copyright and how it affects the GPL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The footnotes hold links to even more good information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It presents ideas without giving real world examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The content is very dense and hard to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be nice to have examples of where different licenses won't work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there any negatives associated with creating open source software?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we create different business models around open source software?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does it mean for the goverments software to be public domain? How is that different from open source software?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being extremely dense and hard to read, this document contains a lot of good information. It is laid out in a way that makes it easier to read.
Half a dozen red roses and one white rose&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSS Legal Primer Lit Review</title><link href="/foss-legal-primer-lit-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-05T14:14:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-05:foss-legal-primer-lit-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Who&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Fontana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bradley M. Kuhn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eben Moglen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew Norwood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel B. Ravicher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karen Sandler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Vasile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aaron Williamson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects - Chapters 1-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bizlegfoss-ritigm.rhcloud.com/static/books/foss-primer.pdf&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank"&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 4, 2008&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A place to start learning about the different types of licenses and other important legal things for people just joining the FOSS community. It's also something that could be good to keep on hand for a refresher in some of the different licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The information is in-depth enough to give good detail, but it's also not in straight legalese, so it's readable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are very clear that this information is just to help get you started and isn't legal advice up front.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This document gives examples of some of the different types of licenses for you to look. It doesn't just explain how they work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's getting "old", in the technological sense, even though it's actually not that old.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list of licenses, and license families, covered is extremely small, while it seems like the list of licenses in existance is much bigger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After saying there was no legal advice in this document, the way the wording is in some portions sounds more like advice on how to handle situations by yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does working on a project for a class and then continuing on that project as a paid project affect the ownership of the project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the AGPL in what form does your source code have to be offered? Does it have to be shipped with the software, or can it just be made available via the internet?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do non-compete clauses aversely affect the FOSS community?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Foss Legal Primer has a lot of good information. It is very in-depth when it needs to be, but not so much as to make it unreadable for your average person.
Half a dozen red roses and a white rose&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category><category term="HFOSS"></category></entry><entry><title>Everything Is a Remix - Video Review</title><link href="/everything-is-a-remix-video-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-05T11:59:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Alexandria Mack</name></author><id>tag:,2015-02-05:everything-is-a-remix-video-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Who&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;StarveTheSystem2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Where&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=coGpmA4saEk&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 25, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy, Transform, Combine. This is the basis of all creativity. Intelectual Property has overtaken the idea of the common good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is an extremely well thought out argument. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When he was talking about the videos his visuals were extremely helpful.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For people who already use ideas from other places and just combine them in different ways it's nice to know other people have done it too. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There wasn't a link in the description to their sources page. I had to dig into their website. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When he was talking about everything besides the videos the visuals were extremely distracting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It could be very disheartening for a person who thinks their ideas are original to realize that they might not be. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does everyone purposely use other things the way George Lucas did, or is it done accidentally?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why did James Kirby make this video?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is it actually determined if code has been copied?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is a Remix is an interesting way to show how many of our famous works, including videos, songs, and code, are all derivatives. 
Half a dozen red roses and three white roses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="BizLeg"></category></entry></feed>